<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
  <string-array name="initial_story_list" formatted="false">
    <!-- Each story has 7 items:
         * title
         * author
         * headline
         * description
         * download url
         * zip file entry name (empty if not in a zip file)
         * cover image url
      -->

    <item>Adventure</item>
    <item>Will Crowther and Don Woods (reconstructed by Donald Ekman, David M. Baggett and Graham Nelson)</item>
    <item>The interactive original</item>
    <item>Adventure aka Colossal Cave, the original 350 points version ported to Inform by Graham Nelson, based on Dave Baggett\'s TADS reconstruction &quot;Collossal Cave Revisited&quot;. Release 9 /Serial number 060321</item>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/zcode/Advent.z5</item>
    <item/>
    <item>http://ifdb.tads.org/showimage?id=4%3A650</item>

    <!-- featuring this in screen shots is probably not a good idea given major distributor -->
    <item>Zork I</item>
    <item>Dave Lebling and Marc Blank</item>
    <item>The Great Underground Empire</item>
    <item>Discover the &quot;Great Underground Empire&quot; and find out how gruesome a &quot;Grue&quot; is!</item>
    <item>http://www.infocom-if.org/downloads/zork1.zip</item>
    <item>DATA/ZORK1.DAT</item>
    <item>http://www.infocom-if.org/games/zork1/zork1front_th.jpg</item>

    <item>Zork II</item>
    <item>Dave Lebling and Marc Blank</item>
    <item>The Wizard of Frobozz</item>
    <item>Enter the realm of the Wizard of Frobozz, in a long hidden region of the Empire. Adventure galore awaits you!</item>
    <item>http://www.infocom-if.org/downloads/zork2.zip</item>
    <item>DATA/ZORK2.DAT</item>
    <item>http://www.infocom-if.org/games/zork2/zork2front_th.jpg</item>

    <item>Zork III</item>
    <item>Dave Lebling and Marc Blank</item>
    <item>The Dungeon Master</item>
    <item>Enter the deepest, most mysterious parts of the realm and meet the Dungeon Master, who possibly holds the solution to it all!</item>
    <item>http://www.infocom-if.org/downloads/zork3.zip</item>
    <item>DATA/ZORK3.DAT</item>
    <item>http://www.infocom-if.org/games/zork3/zork3front_th.jpg</item>

    <item>Bronze</item>
    <item>Emily Short</item>
    <item>A fractured fairy tale</item>
    <item>Bronze, the demonstration game that accompanies Inform 7, by Emily Short. Release 11 / Serial number 060503</item>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/zcode/Bronze.zblorb</item>
    <item/>
    <item/>

    <item>Rover\'s Day Out</item>
    <item>Jack Welch and Ben Collins-Sussman</item>
    <item/>
    <item>Three hundred years ago, the Brazilian Space Agency discovered a rocky exoplanet only 38 light years from Earth. With a surface temperature of 1200 Celsius and nine times Earth gravity, it\'s hardly the sort of place you\'d tke your dog walkies. Most days.</item>
    <item>http://www.red-bean.com/sussman/if/rover/Rover\'s%20Day%20Out.gblorb</item>
    <item/>
    <item/>

    <item>Six</item>
    <item>Wade Clarke</item>
    <item>An Interactive Fiction</item>
    <item>Your name is Harriet Leitner, and you and your twin sister Demi turned six this morning! You\'re having a fancy dress birthday party, and this afternoon you\'ll be playing Hide and Seek Tip over in the park. You can\'t wait to catch all your friends.</item>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/competition2011/glulx/six/Six.gblorb</item>
    <item/>
    <item/>


    <item>Endless, Nameless</item>
    <item>Adam Cadre</item>
    <item>An Interactive Fiction</item>
    <item>Dial-up BBS system adventure</item>
    <item>http://ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/zcode/nameless.z8</item>
    <item/>
    <item>http://ifdb.tads.org/showimage?id=0%3A325</item>

    <item>Art of Fugue</item>
    <item>Victor Gijsbers, Jimmy Maher, Dorte Lassen and Johan</item>
    <item>Interactive studies in counterpoint</item>
    <item/>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/glulx/ArtOfFugue.gblorb</item>
    <item/>
    <item/>

    <item>Lost Pig</item>
    <item>Grunk / Admiral Jota</item>
    <item>And Place Under Ground</item>
    <item>Winner, Best Game; Winner, Best Writing; Nominee, Best Setting; Nominee, Best Puzzles; Nominee, Best NPCs; Winner, Best Individual NPC; Winner, Best Individual PC; Nominee, Best Use of Medium - 2007 XYZZY Awards</item>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/zcode/LostPig.zblorb</item>
    <item/>
    <item/>

    <item>City of Secrets</item>
    <item>Emily Short</item>
    <item>Espionage/Fantasy, 2003</item>
    <item>Interactive Fiction Top 50 of all time</item>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/glulx/CoS.zip</item>
    <item>CoSv3.blb</item>
    <item>http://ifdb.tads.org/showimage?id=0%3A26</item>

    <item>Anchorhead</item>
    <item>Michael Gentry</item>
    <item>Lovecraftian, 1998</item>
    <item>You take a deep breath of salty air as the first raindrops begin to spatter the pavement, and the swollen, slate-colored clouds that blanket the sky mutter ominous portents amongst themselves over the little coastal town of Anchorhead.</item>
    <item>http://ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/zcode/anchor.z8</item>
    <item/>
    <item>http://ifdb.tads.org/showimage?id=2%3A119</item>

    <item>Blue Lacuna</item>
    <item>Aaron A. Reed</item>
    <item>Science Fiction, 2008</item>
    <item>You have always been different. One in a trillion have your gift, your curse: to move between worlds, never settling, always alone. To Wayfare. Yet there are others like you, and something stronger than coincidence binds you together, bumps your lives against each other like charged particles. </item>
    <item>http://blue-lacuna.textories.com/release/BlueLacuna-r4.zip</item>
    <item>BlueLacuna-r4.gblorb</item>
    <item></item>

    <item>Slouching Towards Bedlam</item>
    <item>Star Foster and Daniel Ravipinto</item>
    <item>Steampunk, 2003; Inform 7 10th Anniversary release</item>
    <item>In the beginning was the Word, and it was hungry. Enter a steampunk adventure set in a London that might have been. The year is 1885. Bedlam Hospital still stands in Moorsfield, a decaying shell used to house the poor and the hopeless. Steam-driven mechanical wonders roam the streets. Gear-wheeled analytical engines spin out reams of thought onto punched paper tapes. And in the darkness - in the alleys and the side shops - hide secrets.</item>
    <item formatted="false">http://www.peccable.com/if/slouching-10/src/Slouching%20Towards%20Bedlam.gblorb</item>
    <item/>
    <item/>

    <item>Coloratura</item>
    <item>Lynnea Glasser</item>
    <item>Horror, 2013</item>
    <item>Stolen away by apathetic Blind Ones, your only desire is to return to your Cellarium and the Song of the Universe. They should understand. You shall make them to understand.</item>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/competition2013/glulx/coloratura/Coloratura.gblorb</item>
    <item/>
    <item/>

    <item>Brain Guzzlers from Beyond!</item>
    <item>Steph Cherrywell</item>
    <item>Humor, 2015</item>
    <item>You are Bonnie Noodleman, Ordinary Well-Adjusted Teen-Ager, on an ordinary well-adjusted drive up Make-Out Mountain—until some gooey monstrosity from beyond the stars guzzles your boyfriend\'s brains clean out of his head! Jeepers, what a pickle! Can you convince the townsfolk you\'re not koo-koo, or is your thinker next on the alien menu? Explore beautiful Canyonville, New Mexico, at the height of the 1959 Pine Nut Days festival, interact with a full cast of NPCs, perform beat poetry, tamper with baked goods, use hideously powerful space weapons to win cheap carnival trinkets, and try to avoid getting a Reputation!</item>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/glulx/Brain_Guzzlers_from_Beyond%21.gblorb</item>
    <item/>
    <item/>

    <item>The Moon Watch</item>
    <item>Paolo Maroncelli and Alessandro Peretti</item>
    <item>Society / Space, 2008</item>
    <item>Winner, Best Use of Medium - 2008 XYZZY Awards: You\'re an ordinary Soviet citizen, but to your surprise you are selected to play a highly important part in the defence of the Motherland - and then the crisis comes…</item>
    <item>http://www.maroncelli.net/wp-content/uploads/2008/12/moonwatch.zip</item>
    <item>moonwatch.blb</item>
    <item formatted="false">http://ifdb.tads.org/showimage?id=0%3A145</item>

    <item>Make It Good</item>
    <item>Jon Ingold</item>
    <item>An Interactive Detective Story, 2009</item>
    <item>The call comes through. Of all the dicks; you get the call, sitting in the front seat of your car, hands shaking on the steering wheel. An urgent call; but all you were thinking of was the bottle in the liquor store and so that\'s where you went first. Now you\'re pulled up outside the house. The rear mirror\'s showing two steely eyes. You adjust your hat, stiffen up your collar and grab your badge off the dash. Here goes. You\'ve one last chance so…</item>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/zcode/MakeItGood.zblorb</item>
    <item></item>
    <item></item>

    <item>Ether</item>
    <item>MathBrush (Brian Rushton)</item>
    <item>Science fiction, 2015</item>
    <item>A game about a flying cephalopod and its airy world. This short adventure recreates the feel of exploring a world in a graphical game, and uses a 9x9x9 cubical grid. Navigate the world in 26 directions as you collect items and use the properties of your environment to unlock their power. An in-game walkthrough is included, as are instructions for those new to parser interactive fiction, where you type in commands.</item>
    <item>http://ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/competition2015/Ether/Ether.gblorb</item>
    <item></item>
    <item></item>

    <item>Color the Truth</item>
    <item>MathBrush (Brian Rushton)</item>
    <item>Mystery, 2016</item>
    <item>Rosalita Morales is dead, and you have to figure out who did it. The four people closest to her had the motive and the means: her partner, her secretary, her ex-husband, and her sister. Re-live their memories of Rosalita\'s last days to discover what really happened. But be careful: Everyone has something to hide, and everyone will Color the Truth. Color the Truth is conversation-based murder mystery game that takes roughly 2 hours to finish. It is designed to be accessible to players who have never tried parser games, and comes with adaptive hints accessible by typing HINT.</item>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/glulx/Color_the_Truth.gblorb</item>
    <item></item>
    <item></item>

    <item>Moon-Shaped</item>
    <item>Jason Ermer</item>
    <item>Fantasy, 2006</item>
    <item>When thirteen year old Rosalind tires of her mother\'s angst, she sets off to grandmother\'s house for good food and better company. But upon arriving, she finds an empty house, a half-twisted quilt, and a full-on mystery. Thus begins her quest through space, memory and a closet full of skeletons.</item>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/zcode/Moon-Shaped.zblorb</item>
    <item></item>
    <item></item>

    <item>Hunger Daemon</item>
    <item>Sean M. Shore</item>
    <item>Humor, 2014</item>
    <item>It\'s not the end of the world, and you\'re to blame. Better get on that. But man, it sure would be nice to get a bite to eat first.</item>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/glulx/Hunger_Daemon.gblorb</item>
    <item></item>
    <item></item>

    <item>Coloratura</item>
    <item>Lynnea Glasser</item>
    <item>Horror, 2013</item>
    <item>Stolen away by apathetic Blind Ones, your only desire is to return to your Cellarium and the Song of the Universe. They should understand. You shall make them to understand.</item>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/competition2013/glulx/coloratura/Coloratura.gblorb</item>
    <item></item>
    <item></item>


    <item>The Hitchhiker\'s Guide to the Galaxy</item>
    <item>Douglas Adams and Steve Meretzky</item>
    <item>Don\'t Panic!</item>
    <item>Relax, because everything you need to know about playing The Hitchhiker\'s Guide to the Galaxy is contained in the pages of this manual. In this story, you will be Arthur Dent, a rather ordinary earth creature who gets swept up in a whirlwind of interstellar adventures almost beyond comprehension.</item>
    <!--
    <item>http://www.myabandonware.com/media/files/games/t/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy.zip</item>
    <item>hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy/HITCHHIK.DAT</item>
    <item>http://ifdb.tads.org/showimage?id=0%3A43</item>
    -->
    <item>http://www.douglasadams.com/creations/hhgg.z3</item>
    <item></item>
    <item>http://ifdb.tads.org/showimage?id=0%3A43</item>

    <item>Toby\'s Nose</item>
    <item>Chandler Groover</item>
    <item>Mystery, 2015</item>
    <item>A murder most foul has been committed and Sherlock Holmes is on the case. You are his dog.</item>
    <item>http://www.castleprincessdragon.com/InteractiveFiction/TobysNose/Toby\'s%20Nose.gblorb</item>
    <item></item>
    <item></item>


    <item>Foo Foo</item>
    <item>Buster Hudson</item>
    <item>Mystery, 2016</item>
    <item>Someone\'s been bopping the field mice on the head, and only Good Fairy, Senior Detective can find out who.  A parser-driven noir adventure based on the interactive fiction of Ryan Veeder.</item>
    <item>http://ifarchive.org/if-archive/games/springthing/2016/FooFoo.gblorb</item>
    <item></item>
    <item></item>

    <item>Casa Tomada</item>
    <item>Daniel Garrido</item>
    <item>Mystery, 2005</item>
    <item>Spanish language. Episode 5 of Mystery House Taken Over</item>
    <item>http://mirror.ifarchive.org/if-archive/art/mhto/mhto-dhan.blb</item>
    <item></item>
    <item>http://ifdb.tads.org/showimage?id=1%3A47</item>

    <item>Glulxercise</item>
    <item>Andrew Plotkin</item>
    <item>A Glulx interpreter unit test</item>
    <item>a unit test that runs through all the Glulx opcodes and features</item>
    <item>http://www.eblong.com/zarf/glulx/glulxercise.ulx</item>
    <item/>
    <item/>

    <!--
    <item>Sensory Jam</item>
    <item>Andrew Plotkin</item>
    <item>A Quick Glulx Demo</item>
    <item/>
    <item>http://www.eblong.com/zarf/glulx/sensory.blb</item>
    <item/>
    <item/>
    -->

  </string-array>


  <string name="ifarchive_scrape_week_url">http://mirror.ifarchive.org/indexes/date_1.html</string>
  <string name="ifarchive_scrape_month_url">http://mirror.ifarchive.org/indexes/date_2.html</string>
  <string name="ifarchive_scrape_3months_url">http://mirror.ifarchive.org/indexes/date_3.html</string>
  <string name="ifarchive_scrape_year_url">http://mirror.ifarchive.org/indexes/date_4.html</string>
  <string name="ifarchive_download_url">http://mirror.ifarchive.org</string>
  <integer name="ifarchive_cache_timeout">604800000</integer>

  <string-array name="ifdb_scrape_urls">
    <item>http://ifdb.tads.org/random</item>
    <item>http://ifdb.tads.org/random?t=high-rated</item>
    <item>http://ifdb.tads.org/random?t=recent</item>
  </string-array>
  <string name="ifdb_download_info_url">http://ifdb.tads.org/dladviser?xml&amp;os=MacOSX&amp;id=%s</string>
  <string name="ifdb_cover_image_url">http://ifdb.tads.org/viewgame?coverart&amp;id=%s&amp;thumbnail=300x300</string>
  <integer name="ifdb_cache_timeout">60000</integer>
</resources>
